# 看看晶莹剃透
Look, it’s crystal clear.
# 今天终于见面了
Today, finally we are on the stage.
# 本来老饭骨
Originally, Lao Fan Gu
# 应该我们哥仨在一块
should be the three old brothers of us together.
# 特殊的非常时期
But it is in a special situation,
# 我们不能在一块
we cannot meet each other.
# 请大家原谅
Please forgive us.
# 网友有个私信
a fan left a message,
# 要求红烧肉 五花三层
that he requested Red Braised Pork with pork belly.
# 在这基础上你看
and under that,
# 我们配了小红萝卜
we also use radish.
# 这红萝卜的作用
You know what
# 这个季节是正当时
It's the season for enjoying radish now.
# 这个肉加点葱姜泡一宿
We use green onion and ginger water to soak the meat over night.
# 泡一宿冲干净把水空完了之后
Then, clean and drain the meat on the next day.
# 我们再进行炒
And then we will fry it.
# 这样就把肉的脏腥味全部拿掉了
This way helps to remove all the bad odors in the meat.
# 师父您给我们做的红烧肉
Mater, for this dish,
# 是传统的红烧肉
are you going to make a traditional red braised pork
# 还是有创新点的红烧肉
or an innovative red braised Pork?
# 我们这有点创新点
There are some innovative ideas in it.
# 小魏你说最终的结果是什么
Wei, what do you think the final result is?
# 最终的结果就是好吃好看好玩
The final result? Should be delicious, good looking and fun!
# 第一步 肉咱改工完了
First step, we've done cutting the meat.
# 然后小萝卜有根我们都去掉了
And cut the root of radish.
# 小樱桃萝卜漂亮 水分足
These radishes are beautiful, hydrated.
# 你别瞧看似一个普通的菜
Although it’s a common dish,
# 我给你们讲 它有它的内涵
you know what, it has tricky points.
# 肉的香味全部滋进萝卜里了
The flavor of meat will penetrate into radish.
# 特别好吃
It will taste so good.
# 萝卜喜荤
Radish and meat are a good pairing,
# 比方说广东菜的萝卜牛腩
like the Cantonese dish "Luobo Niunan" (beef brisket with radish).
# 这个为了让它入味
To make the flavor penetrate,
# 轻轻地拍一下
we slightly smash it.
# 拍裂就行
As long as you see the cracks.
# 还不能变形 不能拍开了是吧
You still need to keep the original shape, don’t smash it over.
# 好了 可以了
okay, that’s it.
# 这些料再看一看
Let’s see the spices:
# 八角 桂皮
star anise, cinnamon;
# 用这料不要特别多 淡淡的就够了
don’t use too much of these spices, just leave a mild flavor;
# 一个白蔻一点香叶
one white cardamom, some bay leaves,
# 一个葱一个姜
one green onion, one piece of ginger,
# 还有点蒜 香菜 足够了
some garlic, cilantro and that’s enough.
# 炸点葱油是吧
Fry some onion oil, right?
# 叫它充分的能给它吸收了
Make sure the green onion is infused into the oil.
# 这些东西就够了
this is all we need.
# 洋葱来几片 行了
and some onions, good.
# 这时候咱可以把加姜先放上
We can put the ginger first,
# 姜味先出来
so the flavor of ginger comes out first.
# 你要做红烧肉怎么个做法
How would you cook the red braised pork?
# 没做过葱烧红烧肉
I’ve never use onion oil to make red braised pork.
# 先炼葱油 这是第一回
It’s my first time to make onion oil first.
# 创新的目的是为了什么
What's the purpose of innovation?
# 是为了把我们的菜做得更好
To make the dish better.
# 因为现在跟我们过去不一样
Because it’s different from the past now.
# 过去原材料它非常好
The raw materials were too good in the past.
# 所以说现在我们需要把这些
That’s why we need to make sure that,
# 比如肉也好鱼也好
like when preparing meat or fish,
# 可能异味的东西比较重一些
or those with stronger odors
# 处理掉 让它更加香
Get rid of the odors, make it more tasty.
# 其实这是最终的目的
This is our final goal.
# 味道是王道
Flavor is most important.
# 油温上来了 葱放里边
The oil is hot, put green onion in it.
# 慢慢的炸吧
Slowly fry them.
# 小葱油你看 香气出来了
Onion oil. Look, the aroma gets out.
# 其实用葱油最讲究的还是山东菜
Shandong cuisine is the most particular one about onion oil.
# 多炸它一会
Fry them longer.
# 师父应该是炸到金黄色吧 金黄色
Master, we should fry until the color changes to golden yellow, right?
# 过去做红烧肉基本不飞水
In the past, we basically didn't parboil for red braised pork
# 炒糖色之后 用糖直接裹直接粘
We just used caramelized sugar to cover the meat directly.
# 粘上糖其实它有什么
The purpose of using caramelized sugar are,
# 一个是收缩的作用
one is to make the meat tight,
# 在裹制当中 把肉紧实了
during the covering process, it shrinks the meat.
# 还有一种去腥的作用
the other one is remove the bad odors.
# 实际上我们做事
In fact, when we do things,
# 成功在于什么 在于细节
success lies in the details.
# 细节在哪儿呢
What are the details?
# 当年在酒店来的第一件事干嘛
When I first worked in a restaurant, the first thing I did was...
# 师父 时候到了吧
Master, this is good right?
# 上料 上汤
Prepare the aromatics. The sauce.
# 所有的油 必须拿葱炸香给我炸出来
All the oil has to fry the onions first,
# 油永远是熟的永远是带有香味的
so the oil is always cooked and flavorful.
# 这时候我们把肉拿来 葱油
Now we get the meat, onion oil.
# 你闻这满屋子葱香味
The room is full of the aroma from fried onion.
# 其实你通过气味的变化
In fact, through the changes in the aroma,
# 你就能明白这个菜香不香
you can judge if the dish is flavor or not,
# 出来好不好
if it will be good or not.
# 慢慢的煸  肉就收缩了
Slowly stir-fry it, the meat will shrink.
# 这油脂全出来了 不腻了
The fat goes out so the meat will not be greasy.
# 现在就很有食欲了
It looks tasty.
# 比如说我们要炖个鸡
For instance, if we are going to stew a chicken.
# 这个鸡块 你炸完了之后再炖
Which do you think is more flavorful?
# 你是不炸 你直接炖
The chicken pieces you have fried first,
# 你看哪个香
or the one you don’t fry.
# 这颜色起来了吧
Look at the color change.
# 大家看一看啊
Everyone look at it.
# 多余的油不要了
We don't need the excess oil.
# 水油炒 水油混合炒
Cook the white rock sugar with both oil and water.
# 冰糖 都搁里头
Put the white rock sugar in it.
# 搁点水混合炒
Add some water and fry it.
# 师父我想问个问题
Master, I have a question,
# 它的好处在哪里
Why should we use white rock suger?
# 为什么都用冰糖呢
What’s good about it?
# 它更亮
It’s brighter.
# 不行呢不行呢 现在不行
Not yet.
# 等会颜色还不到 不到时候
It’s not the right color yet.
# 你看看大泡变小泡
Look, the big bubbles turn to small ones.
# 颜色渐渐就变了 变成深褐色了
The color slowly changes to dark brown.
# 小魏 差不多了吧
Wei, that’s good.
# 小魏可以了
Wei, it’s enough.
# 这颜色你看看 恰到好处
Look at this color, just right.
# 来点这个 料酒 好
And some cooking wine.
# 你看这颜色
look at the color.
# 烹了点酒 酒香味十足
It smells good.
# 用点葱油
Add some onion oil.
# 这两块（大料）够么 够了
Two star anises? Yeah.
# 桂皮搁里边 一片香叶
Add cinnamon and one piece of bay leaf.
# 把这肉再煸炒一下
Restir the meat.
# 二次回锅煸炒
Stir-fry the meat again.
# 黄酒 来一瓶啊师父 来一瓶都没事
- Rice wine. The whole bottle, master?
- That's fine.
# 这个香啊 味道出来了
It smells so tasty.
# 炒糖色
Add some caramelized sugar.
# 家里边我们可以不用搁酒也行
We don’t have to use rice wine back at home.
# 然后放点开水
And then add some boiled water.
# 可以放点酱油
Add some soy sauce,
# 调味 加点糖
season with suger.
# 搁糖有什么作用啊
What’s the purpose of adding sugar?
# 主要提鲜又平衡味道
Mainly to enhance the umami taste and balance the flavor.
# 慢慢的小火炖着 咱再来点盐
slowly simmer it without too much heat, and add some salt.
# 盐定定味儿
Salt it.
# 慢慢的红烧肉咱就小火烧
Now slowly simmer it without too much heat.
# 焖会吧喝点水 待会儿就熟了
Simmer for a bit. Drink some water, it will be done later.
# 五十多分钟不到一个小时了
It’s about 50 mintues, less than an hour.
# 都差不多了
It's basically done.
# 萝卜呢 萝卜咱炸啊
For radish, we fry them first.
# 咱先搁到这火上
put it on stove first.
# 炸萝卜 师兄我来
Fry radish, Brother I can do it.
# 说说油温
Speaking about oil temperature,
# 九十到一百三十度 这是一个温度
90 to 130 degrees is a range,
# 一百三到一百七 这是中性
130 to 170, this range is called medium.
# 师父开始炸小萝卜了准备
Master is preparing to fry radish.
# 一百七到二百三
170 to 230,
# 这是一个最高的温度
this is the highest range.
# 在做菜当中其实应该是
There are three ranges to
# 用三个温度去控制
control the heat during cooking.
# 我们制作的菜品
when we cook,
# 这一百三实际上就是四成
130 degree is about 40 percent.
# 这个油温度适合做什么啊
what is this temperature good for?
# 像滑溜肉片 滑炒的东西
Like Hua Liu Meat, those kind of things.
# 滑炒非常之嫩 入口即化
With that technique, the food is so tender that it melts in the mouth.
# 最高点一百七到二百三
the highest range is 170 to 230 degrees.
# 这温度适合炸菜
This is good for deep frying.
# 松鼠鱼 脆皮等等的系列的
Like Squirrel fish, or those with crispy skin.
# 没味儿怎么弄啊 前期入味
What should we do if it’s not flavorful? Season it in advance.
# 因为萝卜它不容易进味
As radish doesn't absorb too much flavor.
# 油我已经听到响声了啊
I can hear the sound from the oil.
# 这个皮 这东西是最去腥的
This peel is more useful to remove those bad odors.
# 过去发那些特别腥的 用这个最棒
In the past this was the best to remove the bad odors.
# 你们家有橘子皮没有
Do you have tangerine peel at home?
# 搁两块你看 它确实是去腥
Add two pieces. It removes the bad odors.
# 好油温差不多了
Okay, oil temperature is good.
# 漂亮跟紫菜头一样
It’s beautiful as nori.
# 你看那盐没有
Look at the salt.
# 盐还有保鲜护色的作用
Salt also protects the skin color.
# 你看要不早变颜色了
Yeah, you see, otherwise the color would change.
# 漂亮
Beautiful.
# 下锅
Back to the pot.
# 又漂亮又入味
It’s beautilful and flavorful.
# 看这红烧肉你看 你看这汁儿收的
Look at this Red Braised Pork, look at this gravy.
# 晶莹剃透
It’s crystal clear.
# 桂皮 香叶拣出来 挑出来
Pick the cinnamon and bay leaves out.
# 大火催它一下齐活
Put it on high heat.
# 出锅喽来喽
Ready to serve!
# 当年我在华都的时候
When I was at Huadu (hotel),
# 我们就用口布去装饰
We used napkin to decorate.
# 其实自然也很美
Actually, it's already beautiful on its own.
# 端一个来拍一个
Come on, let’s take a picture.
# 漂亮
Beautiful.
# 师兄的动作也比较优美啊
Brother, your camera movements are fine, too.
# 手都打哆嗦 想吃肉了
Your hands are shaking. You want to eat it.
# 别急啊师兄
No rush, brother.
# 做菜应该精益求精吧
We should seek for perfection in cooking.
# 来 取个镜
take a shot.
# 师父做这红烧肉
This red braised pork Master made,
# 肥而不腻 瘦而不柴
is fat but not greasy, lean but not insipid.
# 入口即化 唇齿留香
It melts in the mouth and the flavor remains.
# 有师父的地儿就是家
Home is where Master is.
# 谢谢师父 感谢你们俩
Thank you Master, thank you both.
# 感谢师父
Thank you, Master
# 最好吃的红烧肉
The best red braised pork
# import ending.srt 00:07:42,600